Let's see how we can create the shared VPC.
Let's go to the Google admin console.
For shared VPC, we will make one project, and we make it as a host.
So let's click here and say New project.
I call it ps‑example‑host, say Create.
Now I'm going to create a shared VPC within this host.
And I have two separate projects,
and what I'm trying to do is I'm going to create an instance in
each of those two projects and show how they can talk to each
other without sharing actually anything.
Now, inside this project, go to the VPC network and go to the Shared VPC.
Now click on Set up Shared VPC, say Enable and continue.
So it got enabled, now it is working, and say Continue and say Save.
Now let's go to the VPC network and Create, now give a name as corp‑vpc‑ps.
I keep everything as it is.
Give a name for subnet, vpc‑subnet‑ps.
It will ask to select the region,
so I select the region, and I will select the IP range and say Create.
Now we have created a VPC which has the subnet.
Now I have two already projects.
One is hpc3 and another one is hpc2.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to attach both of these projects to my
shared VPC. I have to just come down here to Shared VPC,
and within the Shared VPC, I click on Attached projects and say Attach projects.
Now let me select the project.
I'm selecting here hpc2, say Save.
Similarly, adding one more project, that is hpc3.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to create one
instance in hpc2 and another instance in hpc3,
and I will show you how both of these two different machines from two
different projects talk to each other because of the shared VPC.
Go to hpc2.
I'm adding one compute machine.
Say Create instance, selecting the region,
and importantly, under the Networking,
I'm going to select the network, which is already shared with me,
and under that I'm going to select the subnet and say Create.
Now this network option, if you are seeing it,
that means your project is correctly attached.
Now, similarly, in another tab, I'm selecting the hpc3 project.
I'm going to create a compute engine as well,
selecting the region and again under the networking here also,
I'll be able to see the network interface that is shared with me,
ps‑example‑host project and subnet is called vpc‑subnet.
Again, I'll do the same thing, say Create here.
Now both of these two instances get created.
One is in project 2.
Another one is in project 3.
Now let me come down here and say SSH for this project 2 one.
The internal IP address for project 2 is 10.10.0.4.
The authorized will be able to do SSH.
Now go down to the project 3.
So I'm doing the SSH inside this as well.
The IP address for this is 10.10.0.5.
Say Authorize.
Now this is the window of our project 3 instance.
Now I'm doing here ping and call 10.10.0.4.
That is, I'm pinging the instance which is in the project 2,
and you can see that it is able to talk to that.
Now on similar lines, I'm coming down to this project 2 instance,
and here I'm saying ping 10.10.0.5, the machine which is in the project 3,
and you can see that from project instance, I can
talk to the project 3 instance.
So both of these are able to talk to each other because
they are sharing the common shared VPC,
and that's how in the real‑world when projects have multiple microservices,
so those projects talk to each other by having the shared network.